#### **LEMUEL CHAO**

Lynnwood, WA 98087 | (425) 835-3545 | lemuel.chao@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/lemuel-chao

# JAVA DEVELOPER/DEVOPS

Java Developer/DevOps professional skilled in building software solutions. Bringing extensive experience in Java, spring boot, microservices, AWS, relational database, and Linux bash scripting. Possess a deep understanding of full software development life cycle and ability to monitor production systems to ensure high availability and performance.

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

Software Development | Application Development | Release Support | Code Optimization

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

C++ | Java/J2EE | DevOps | AWS | Spring boot | SQL | SoapUI
Bash script | Angular JS | Ruby | Python
Kubernetes | Docker and Redis
Linux | Jenkins | Git | Ansible | JSON | XML | HTML
Build and Deliver automation
eCommerce Platform | ATG | SQL developer
Telecom test and Diagnostics

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Arthur Lawrence/Deloitte/New HEIGHTS, NH EASY Java Developer

Jan 2024- Jun 2024

Design, implementation, integration of adult protection service API, waiver search and dashboard

- Quickly setup the local dev environment, dig through the code base and start contribute after orientation.
- Design and implement the APIs associated to online report for adult protection service.
- Implement the search APIs for waiver request, and waiver dashboard.
- Provide quick fixes for integration and team collaboration.
- Provide meaningful sessions, documentations for new joiners to get started quickly.

Self-learning July 2023– Jan 2024

Gone through self-training for the below items.

- Spring boot, spring cloud and spring security
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript and Angular
- MongoDB, Kafka

# Apex Systems/American Family Insurance Java Developer

**August 2021- April 2023** 

Integration and Implementation of payment services APIs such as charging customer profiles, refunding and voiding transactions, and creating and modifying customer and payment profiles. Implementation handles payment-related requests from customers and raw responses from the payment vendor (Auth.net).

 Enabled several hundred disabled unit test cases, enforced check style across legacy applications that deployed as microservices, and enforced code quality using spot bug tool for legacy quote-service applications.

- Logging improvements across legacy applications by identifying places within legacy code base then discussing with team to determine and add proper levels of logging at identified places. Verified log via data dog and troubleshoot logging errors.
- Upgraded the log4j across the branches and pods managed by Kubernetes and the spring boot application to run compatible with Java 11.
- Handled bug fixes, dev maintenance, and release support initiatives.
- Production and QA environments monitoring / debugging via EKS, EC2 and Cloud Watch

# Infogain/Costco Travel

January 2021-August 2021

## Java Developer

Provided payment feature implementation to enable tokenization with vendors.

- Implemented fixes for the Consumer/Agent app.
- Implement the API updates for Hotel and Cruise cabin bookings
- Added unit and integration tests to improve code coverage.
- Led the offshore team and provide monthly reports.

# Accenture/CalSAWS

October 2020-January 2021

## Java Developer

Provided quick fixes for Git merge and defects.

- Integration and implementation of batch modules in Java to cleanup Oracle database according to purge standards and generate PDF files using the data stored in Oracle database, and then upload the files to AWS S3 for long term storage.
- Added multi-threading capabilities for PDF creation and case deletion processes.

## Accenture/AT&T

December 2017-September 2020

#### Java Developer

Provided Java implementations in two-week sprints according to client's business goals and requirements for Store, Care, and e-bonding.

- Implement BAN account one line restriction feature. FirstNet Branding, enterprise new order via e-bonding.
- Resolved defects from monthly release cycles and provided configuration suggestions to QA team.
- Identified and provided solutions for testing issues encountered in profile and catalog management consoles.
- Provided knowledge transfer sessions and introduced multiple tools/plug-ins for onboarding new personnel.
- Validated thousands of promotions and products in Excel files against data in Oracle database and runtime cache.

## Accenture/T-Mobile

June 2015-November 2017

## **DevOps Engineer**

Handled weekly and monthly releases for client web applications to AWS Cloud.

- Managed Jenkins for automated build and deployment processes in multiple testing environments and production.
- Wrote custom Java programs to supplement the CI/CD process such as auto email generation and host inventory generation.
- Troubleshot various environment and application issues related to OAuth, certificate, EC2, load balancer, Jenkins, AEM and Apache web server.
- Created bash scripts to run inside Jenkins job configuration for CI/CD process.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Computer Science & Software Engineering
University of Washington | Bothell (2013-2015)
Dean's List

## **COURSEWORK**

Mathematical Principles of Computing | Data Structures and Algorithms | Software Engineering | Analysis and Design | Database Systems | Hardware and Computer Organization | Data Management principles | Network Design | Operating Systems | Multimedia data processing.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate (2020) SAFe Practitioner (SP) (2019) SAFe Agilest (SA) (2016)